passport.com.ph 2015-06-12

# DFA Passport Appointment System

This policy determines how the information we receive about you when you visit the main DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website (www.passport.com.ph) or any of our pages (collectively "the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s)") is handled. Protection of your privacy and personal data is of utmost importance to us. Protecting your privacy and your personal information is an important aspect of the way we create, organize and implement our activities on-line and off-line. 

## Linkages Characteristics

The specific practices outlined in this privacy statement apply to the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s). You are encouraged to review the privacy statements of other bodies/entities when visiting their websites. 

## Purpose Specifications and Data Collection

Overall, you can browse the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s) without disclosing any information about yourself. If you visit the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s) to read information, we will collect and store only the following information that is automatically recognized: the date and time, the originating IP address, the domain name, the type of browser and operating system used (if provided by the browser), the URL of the referring page (if provided by the browser). 

If you visit the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s) to get an appointment schedule, we collect and store as mandated by the DFA the following information: Application Type, Last Name, First Name, Middle Name, Birthday (mm/dd/yyyy),Birth Place, Birth Right, Gender, Civil Status, Father's Last Name, Father's First Name, Father's Middle Name, Father's Citizenship, Mother's Last Maiden Name, Mother's First Name, Mother's Middle Maiden Name, Mother's Citizenship, Purpose of Travel, Acquired Citizenship, Foreign Passport Holder?, Occupation, Office Number, Office Address, Phone Number, Mobile Number, Email, Philippine Address, City, Province, Landmarks, Deliver My Passport, Processing Type 

## Cookies and Other Technologies

As described above, we sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our website(s) to help us provide better service. We use the information that we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different areas of our website(s), and to help us make our website(s) more useful to visitors. This includes analysing these logs periodically to measure the traffic through our servers, the number of pages visited and the level of demand for pages and topics of interest. The logs may be preserved indefinitely and used at any time and in any way to prevent security breaches and to ensure the integrity of the data on our servers. 

We collect the anonymous information we mentioned above through the use of various technologies, one of which is called "cookies". A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive. The following information is stored in the cookies: 

  * IP address
  * Unique ID
  * Session Token

We do not associate the information stored in a visitor's cookie with any other personal data about that visitor. All our employees and customer care officers who have access to personal data and are associated with the processing of that data are bound and obliged to respect the confidentiality of data. 

## Visitor's Choice

Registering to get an appointment in our website(s) is optional. If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s). However, you will not be able to schedule an appointment or receive e-mail alerts. The DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM views the applicant’s information that it collects as a valuable and confidential asset of which we take great care to ensure its safety in coordination with the Department of Foreign Affairs and the laws pertaining to passport application and processing. 

## Security

We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personal information. The DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM has implemented technologies and security policies to protect the stored personal data of our users from unauthorized access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. We will continue to enhance our security procedures, as new technology becomes available. DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM employees and processors who have access to personal data are bound and obliged to respect the privacy of our visitors and the confidentiality of their personal data. 

## Links

Within the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website(s), you may find links to third party websites. For example, our NSO Online website includes a link to a third party Web server for NSO requests by phone and online payments. Please note that the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM is not responsible for the privacy policies or content on third party sites. 

## Consent Waiver

By using our website, you understand that you are signifying your unequivocal consent to the disclosure, collection and use of the personal information and data described above. Your consent effectively constitutes a waiver of any and all privacy rights pertaining to the disclosure, collection and use of the personal information and data under the specific terms and conditions of DFA Passport Appointment’s Internet Privacy Policy. 

## Changes in Privacy Policy 

As the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM creates new service upgrades that may generate a need to amend this privacy statement, the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM will highlight such changes on the DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM website home page. This privacy policy is effective as of August 1, 2011. If changes in the policy are made, the revised version will be posted here. We suggest that you check here periodically to know the up-to-date version of our privacy policy. However, any changes will not be retroactively applied nor alter how we handle previously collected information. 

## Privacy Support

If you have any inquiries about our privacy statement, please contact:   
DFA PASSPORT APPOINTMENT SYSTEM E-mail: info@passport.com.ph   
URL: www.passport.com.ph
